# Grigoriy Ovchinnikov

# ML Engineer

Georgia, Tbilisi

ML Engineer with more than 5 years of data analysis and machine learning experience. Strong knowledge of classical, advanced ML algorithms, applying deep learning and statistics especially in AdTech domain. Proficiency in working with ML frameworks and databases for business problem-solving.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, GoLang, SQL

Machine learning: Scikit-learn, XGBoost, LightGBM, CatBoost, PyTorch, SciPy, NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib,

Plotly, Seaborn, pulearn, shap, MLflow

Databases & Message broker systems & Workflow orchestration: ClickHouse, PostgreSQL, MongoDB,

Cassandra, HBase, Apache Kafka, Redis, Airflow

Version Control & Deploy & Infrastructure: Git, GitLab CI/CD, Docker(compose, swarm)

GCP: Cloud Functions, Cloud Run, Cloud Storage, PubSub, VertexAI

Big data: Hadoop, Hive, Pyspark

Natural Language Processing: gensim, nltk, transformers, pytorch-lightning

Web scraping: Scrapy, Puppeteer, lxml

Project management: Jira, Confluence, Trello

Other: EDA, Data cleaning, Visualization, Modelling, Propensity Modelling, Model interpretation, Natural

Language Processing, Statistics, Experimental design, Hypothesis testing, MVP

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Go Net | DSP

February 2023 - Present

Limmasol, Cyprus

Senior ML Engineer

- Implemented core machine learning based mechains for DSP: max CPC and target CTR bidding strategies based on control theory methods. Designed and implemented a high-throughput scalable ML model inference service using Go.
- Designed system for contextual targeting feature based on natural language processing and large language modelling(with transformers and PyTorch Lightning).
- Led technical interviews for Machine Learning Engineer roles, enhancing team capabilities.
- MLOps operations: model monitoring, quality assessment, conducting A/B testing. Providing data analysis of collected data to guide decision-making processes.
- Pipeline stack: Python, GoLang, ClickHouse, Kafka, Aerospike, transformers, PyTorch, Redis, Catboost, vowpal-wabbit, gRPC, Prometheus

#### Platforma

November 2020 - December 2022

Data Scientist | ML Engineer

Moscow. Russia

- Implemented state-of-the-art methods for a look-alike modeling task with positive unlabeled (PU) learning using PySpark and PyTorch with a significant uplift in offline and online metrics.
- Built an efficient, accurate and scalable ML solution for labeling clickstream data which increased accuracy and lower inference time on telecom data in more than hundreds of million devices using PySpark and Hadoop.
- Suggested and implemented an NLP-inspired(item2vec) approach for website representation learning based on clickstream data, giving several advantages over the previous approach.
- Pipeline stack: Python, Hadoop, Pyspark, Airflow, PyTorch.

#### S7 TechLab

October 2018 - October 2020

Junior Data Scientist

Moscow, Russia

- Conducted research and data analysis to address predictive maintenance task. Provided estimates of remaining useful life through supervised machine learning in the big data department.
- Developed ML models for improving accuracy of decision support system using cluster analysis and supervised multiclass classification.
- Scraping external data with Python, Building MVP with R Shiny, Python Flask-restx.
- Pipeline stack: Python, Airflow, PySpark, S3, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Cassandra, Kafka.

### **EDUCATION**

### National Research Nuclear University (MEPhI)

Master's degree in Applied Mathematics and Informatics(incomplete)

## September 2018 – June 2020

 $Moscow,\ Russia$ 

## ${\bf Volgograd~State~Technical~University}({\bf VSTU})$

Bachelor's degree in Informatics and Computer Engineering

September 2014 – June 2018 Volgograd, Russia

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Google Cloud, Big Data and Machine Learning Fundamentals [November 2022]
- TensorFlow on Google Cloud [November 2022]
- Drawing conclusions from data, MIPT, Yandex [October 2020]

#### Languages

- English B2(Upper intermediate)
- Russian Native